pressganey.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy | Press Ganey

Untitled Document

Press Ganey Associates, Inc. and all affiliates ("Press Ganey") respect the privacy of all patrons who use our web sites. Our Privacy Policy reflects our intent to protect the private information of all users of our web sites. We urge you to please read this privacy policy as, together with the terms and conditions, it will form the basis for your use of Press Ganey web sites.

Except to the extent required by law, we will not sell, lease, or release your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or other personal data without your consent. Press Ganey does not contribute to or participate in cooperative databases, which give other companies access to such personal information. 

By accessing and using this web site you will be deemed to have read and accepted the terms and conditions, together with the practices set out in this privacy statement.

The information we collect from you may include personal data. We will only collect and process such information as is appropriate and necessary according to the type of services you wish to establish with us. To the extent that the information you provide to us includes personal data, you agree to Press Ganey processing all such personal data for the purposes of providing requested services.

Press Ganey's corporate web site (http://www.pressganey.com) collects and stores only personal information that clients and visitors knowingly provide. 

### Online Behavioral Advertising (“OBA”) Notice

In order to provide you with a better, more personal experience on our Site, Press Ganey (“PG”) uses an Online Behavioral Advertising BA platform called Eloqua to identify how we can better serve your interests. Through Eloqua, PG asks for and maintains the personally identifiable information provided by you to deliver certain services or information to you. “Personally Identifiable Information” means any information that identifies you personally, including, without limitation, your name, e-mail address, password, login ID and other contact information that you voluntarily submit to us. You can also choose not to enter any of their personally identifiable information.

**Information Gathered**  
PG will gather information such as what kind of browser you are on, what operating system you are using, your IP address, cookie information, time stamp (time page accessed as well as time spent per web page) and your click stream information (for example, which pages you have viewed and how long you have been there). Note that information is only gathered while you are on our Site. PG monitors how you arrive at our Site, but cannot and will not gather information about other third party sites you have visited.  PG automatically receives and records such information on our server logs from your browser.

**Cookies**  
PG employs cookies in order for its server to recognize you as a return visitor and unique user. Cookies are small text files placed in the “Cookies” folder on your hard disk and allow PG to remember you. The cookies placed are readable only by PG, and cookies cannot access, read or modify any other data on a computer. All web browsers offer the option to refuse any cookie. If you refuse the cookie, PG does not gather any information on you, but doing so will require you to re-enter certain information at each visit, or prevent us from customizing the site's features according to your preferences. You may also delete a cookie manually from your hard drive. Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

**OBA Opt-Out**  
We provide you the opportunity to “opt-out” of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. If you would like to opt-out please send an e-mail to [optout@pressganey.com](mailto:optout@pressganey.com). 

### Press Ganey Forums

Our Client Forums web sites (https://www.pressganey.com/forum) collects and stores only personal information that clients and visitors knowingly provide. Any information you choose to share when using any of these forums or functions becomes public information.

Do not post any information or other material protected by copyright without the permission of the copyright owner. By uploading information or other material onto the Forum web site, the uploading party warrants and represents that it owns the copyrighted information or other material, or has received permission from the person or entity who owns the copyrighted information or other material. By uploading information or other material onto the Forum web site, the uploading party grants Press Ganey the non-exclusive right and license to display, copy, publish, distribute, transmit, print and use such information or other material. Subject to the grant of this license, the uploading party retains any other rights that the party may have in such information or other material. 

### Information Integrity/Security

To provide a secure environment that is protected from unauthorized third-party access, alteration, theft, or misuse Press Ganey uses industry-standard technology including encryption and firewalls to protect personal information gathered online. To enable us to provide a secure environment, Press Ganey may use personal information internally to diagnose problems or to contact you if necessary. 

### Third-Party Links

This web site and Press Ganey _Briefings_ contain links to other web sites. Press Ganey is not responsible for the content of such web sites including any changes or updates that are made to the linked web site or the accuracy or completeness of the information provided on those web sites. Press Ganey encourages its web site users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

### Press Ganey _Briefings_

Press Ganey _Briefings_ is a monthly email Press Ganey sends containing useful information. If you no longer wish to receive Press Ganey _Briefings_ , you may opt out by clicking the "Unsubscribe" button at the bottom of the _Briefings_ e-mail. 

### Corrections or Updates

If at any time you wish to correct or update information that you have already provided, the information may be changed or modified using the same system that was used to enter the information. 

### Copyright

Press Ganey web sites are created, owned, controlled by, and are the exclusive copyright of Press Ganey Associates unless otherwise stated. Nothing on this web site shall be construed as conferring any license under any intellectual property right, including any right in the nature of trademark or copyright, of Press Ganey or any third party, whether estoppels, implication, or otherwise. Unauthorized use of content or materials from Press Ganey web sites is prohibited. 

### How to Contact Us

To contact us with questions or comments about our privacy statement and practices:

Email us at: [privacy@pressganey.com](mailto:privacy@pressganey.com)

Press Ganey reserves the right to change or update this Privacy Policy at any time.
